rjf.com 2008-05-09

# Raymond James Financial | Privacy notice for Raymond James Clients, including Heritage Family of Funds Customers

| 

## Privacy Notice

Raymond James and the Heritage Family of Funds, administered by its wholly-owned subsidiary Heritage Asset Management, are committed to protecting confidentiality of the information furnished to us by our clients.

We are providing you this information as required by Regulation S-P adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission.

### Information about you that we collect

We collect nonpublic personal information about you, including but not limited to, name, address, social security number and financial information from the following sources: information we receive from you on applications or other forms or through our website; information we receive about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others; and information we may receive from a consumer reporting agency.

### Our use of information about you

As permitted by law, we may share information about you with other companies in the Raymond James family – that is, companies that are owned by Raymond James Financial. That may include information shared by the Heritage Family of Funds with Raymond James broker/dealers and investment advisors, and information shared among other Raymond James financial service providers, such as financial advisors and insurance and annuity consultants. In addition, we may share information about you with certain nonaffiliated third parties, including financial service providers (e.g., mutual fund companies), non-financial companies (e.g., software developers), and others (e.g., consulting firms) in order to help us run our business, manage your accounts, provide professional services, or help us market our products and services to you. Raymond James Financial Services, Inc. is a party to joint marketing arrangements with certain banks and credit unions. Information about clients who participate in these programs may be shared by RJFS with the participating bank or credit union. These financial institutions have agreed to treat any such information as confidential and not to share such information with any other parties. Additionally, financial advisors may change brokerage firms and information may be received or taken by your financial advisor to the new firm. If you do not want your financial advisor to transfer this information, please contact 1 (800) 647-SERV (7378) to opt out of this information sharing. Otherwise, we do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to anyone except as permitted by law. We follow the same policy with respect to nonpublic personal information received from all clients and former clients.

### How we protect your confidential information

Raymond James has policies that restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees, associates, and others who have need for that information to help us run our business, manage your accounts, market or provide investment alternatives or services to you, or to employees, associates, and others who assist those who help us run our business, manage your accounts, or market or provide investment alternatives or services to you. Additionally, we maintain physical, electronic, contractual, and procedural safeguards to protect your nonpublic personal information.

|
